关键是舌头  哥们儿
It's all about the tongue, man.
一直把舌头探在她们嘴里
You stick it in their mouth,
但不是直直的
but not all the way.
-她们喜欢吗  -哥们儿  她们爱死了
- They like that? - Dude, they love it.
-干吗啊  这是  -翻门呀
- What are you doing? - Climbing.
要能舔到她的牙齿
Just deep enough to lick her teeth
慢慢的  一个个舔  就像上色一样
Slow, one at a time, like you're painting them.
这个叫瑞秋的女孩儿  虽说是个小学生
This girl Rachel, she's a junior.
经验那可老了去了
She's experienced.
妈妈让我5点前回家
Mom says I gotta be home by 5:00.
放松点  在有人看到你之前赶紧跳上门
Just chill, okay? And hop the fence before someone sees you.
-真没事吗  -戴夫的妈妈是房地产经纪人
- Are you sure this is okay?  - Dave's mom's a realtor.
待售的空房子就是咱们的小基地
If it's for sale and empty, it's a clubhouse.
要是走漏半点风声  你死定了
And if you say anything, you're dead.
我跟他们说你很酷的
I told them you were cool.
他们可都是纯爷们儿
These are very serious dudes.
来吧
Come on.
童子军聚会在街那边
Cub scout meeting's down the street, boys.
-真他妈弱  -残废
- What a loser. - Lame.
盖布很酷的  咱们可是一伙儿的
Gabe's cool, man. He's one of us.
但愿如此
He better be.
我不渴
Uh, I'm not thirsty.
-这是什么  -小孩  酒吧里的玩意
- What's this? - Club business, little man.
-我们该问什么呢  -把你的手放上去
- What shall we ask? - Put your hands on.
黑暗精灵  今年我们中会有人惨遭不幸吗
Oh, dark spirit, will any of us die in the year to come?
-你们故意的  -把手放回去
- You're moving it. - Put your hands back.
快点
Now.
哪一位会遭遇不测呢
Who among us will die?
盖
"G,"
布
"A"-
天哪
Oh, man.
里
"B,"
尔
"E."
盖布里尔  真糟糕
"Gabe. '" That blows.
不行  我们得去医院
That's it. We're going to the hospital.
不  妈妈  我太累了
No, mom. I'm too tired.
快起床  亲爱的
Come on, sweetie.
你已经烧了一周了
You've had a fever for almost a week now.
天哪
Oh, my god.
盖布  你没事吧
Oh, Gabe. Are you okay?
你没事吧  宝贝  怎么了
Are you okay? Baby, what's wrong?
我要死了
I'm dying.
暮雨身前送  带孝生后随
姥姥一路走好
愿久九Nine的姥姥在天堂一切都好
人人影视豪斯组敬上
12岁男性  典型性峰热  胸闷
Twelve-year-old male. Spiking fever, congested chest,
咳嗽并带有绿色的痰  呼吸伴有疼痛
coughing up green sputum, pain in breathing.
奇了怪啊  我依稀记得有种病叫非炎
Baffling, though I vaguely recall a disease called "Meunomia"?
还是肺什么来着
"Pneumania"?
但是他胸腔的X光和CT
But his chest x-ray and C.T. scan
没有显示出肺炎的典型症状
show an atypical pattern for pneumonia.
还真叫肺炎  就是它
Pneumonia! That's it.
我就猜猜啊  他爸妈给医院捐了不少吧
Just a guess here, but his parents big donors?
没有渗入  只是肺门淋巴结肿大
No infiltrate, just enlarged hilar lymph nodes.
小独角兽刺穿下他的肺就好了
Tiny unicorns goring his bronchial tubes would be cooler,
你在逃避我的问题
and the way you're ignoring the question- wow,
还真是大财主
They're extremely big donors.
头孢呋辛没有疗效
He's not responding to cefuroxime,
如果是肺炎的话
His pulse ox is dropping
他的血氧浓度不应下降这么快
much faster than it should for pneumonia,
他还起了一些疹子
and plus he's got an odd little rash.
过度刺激  12岁是该病的高发年龄
Excessive irritation. He's 12. He's on auto-stroke.
疹子出在他的手臂上
On his arm.
细长的疤上长有一厘米丘疹状病灶
Papular lesion, one centimeter, on top of a long, thin scab.
你该去皮肤科找专家
Ah, you need a dermatologist.
干了补补水
If it's dry, keep it wet.
油了控控油
If it's wet, keep it dry.
要是长错了地方  那就切了
If it's not supposed to be there, cut it off.
我又不是万事通
I never could master all that.
终于找到你了
There you are.
害怕了吧  不用怕  你到家了
Were you scared? It's okay. You're home now.
好吧
Fine.
卡迪
Cuddy.
-卖个人情给你  -得了吧你
- As a special favor to you - No.
认了吧  我用疹子吊上了你的胃口
Admit it. I got you with the rash.
疹子极其无聊
The rash is a total snooze,
但并发肺炎情况就大不一样了
unless it's connected to the pneumonia,
热闹了
Then it's party time.
浓痰  呼吸困难  双肺干罗音
Purulent sputum, dyspnea, rhonchi bilaterally.
哪种肺炎会引发这种皮疹
What kind of pneumonia causes this kind of rash?
军团病[一种高危险性的肺炎]
Legionnaire's disease.
意味着要接触到工业通风系统和会展中心
Usually means industrial ventilation systems, convention centers.
他才12岁
He's 12 years old.
查军团菌尿抗原  看他是否曾与麋鹿共处
Send off a urine antigen and check if he's joined the elks.
-下一个  -真菌性肺炎
- Next? - Fungal.
太棒了  或许房子成了洞窟探险地
Excellent. Maybe the lodge went spelunking.
衣原体肺炎
Chlamydia pneumonia.
12岁的孩子不可能有性生活
Twelve-year-olds don't have sex.
那就是他们的错了
Their mistake.
说完了吗  没别的可能性了吗
That's it? Other possibilities?
或许我们该倒过来想想
What if we're thinking about this backwards?
先出现皮疹  继而引发肺炎
The rash came first, caused the pneumonia.
有想法
Nice.
立克次体[某种微生物]  蜱叮咬
Rickettsial. Tick bite.
幼虫蜱已经开始繁殖
Nymphal ticks are out now.
都是些嗜血的小混蛋
They're bloodthirsty little bastards.
那些疹子可能就是脓包
Rash would be more pustular.
不一定  只有一种皮疹症状与其相符
Not always, and there's only one rash, which fits.
-在新泽西  莱姆病的可能性更大  -好吧
- New Jersey, it's most likely lyme disease. - All right.
持续输液
Let's keep him on fluids...
以防万一  使用头孢呋辛
And the cefuroxime to be safe.
活检皮疹
Biopsy that rash.
找出他的病史
And take another history.
就算我们找不到病因
Even if we don't learn what's causing this,
也必须要了解
we definitely need to know
一个12岁的孩子的活动
if twelve-year-olds are getting any action.
你们在干吗
What are you doing now?
采集疹子里脓水
We're collecting fluids from the rash.
为什么
Why?
他们清楚自己在干什么  杰弗里
They know what they're doing, Jeffrey.
一个无知女人的高度认可啊
Oh, great endorsement coming from the woman who thought it was a nasty cold.
如果我上周就带他...
If I had had him last week-
少叨叨了
This isn't helping.
我们在检查他是否被蜱叮咬
We're checking to see if your son has a tick bite.
盖布  你最近有没有参加露营啊
Gabe, have you been camping recently,
室外体育活动之类的
playing sports outside, anything like that?
体育不是我的强项
I'm not that good at sports.
没去过新地方
No hanging out anywhere new,
-陌生的地方吗  -我们已经问过了
- strange places? - We've been through this.
我们禁止他和邻居疯玩  对吧
We don't let him run wild through the neighborhood, right?
下面这个问题有些尴尬
Okay. This might be a bit delicate.
你有没有过性生活
We need to know if you're sexually active.
你说什么  你以为...
I beg your pardon?
-莱里克先生  我们需要...  -没有
- Mr. Reilich, we need to - No.
没有
Nothing like that.
得替他再做一次CT扫描
We've gotta get another C.T. Scan,
检查一下他的肺
check his lungs again.
-三楼吗  -是的  放射科在...
- Third floor, right? - Yeah, radiology is-
抱歉  非医务人员勿入
Sorry, medical personnel only.
-在哪里做检查  -其实我们已经过了
- Where's the machine? - Well, we passed it, actually.
那间屋子里的气氛有些紧张
A little tension in the room back there.
我想带你出来透透气
Thought you could use a break.
你爸真是...  非常强势
Your dad's a pretty... high-powered guy.
是的  他是一名空军试飞员
Yeah. He was an air force test pilot.
实打实的棒
Real top gun stuff.
他飞Mach 3
Flew Mach 3.
有时不好处吧
Hard to deal with sometimes?
我觉得我更像我妈
Guess I'm more like my mom.
这样
Listen.
我保证替你保守秘密  可我得知道
I promise to keep my mouth shut, but I need to know.
你真的没有过任何形式的性生活吗
You definitely haven't had any sexual contact of any kind?
我倒是想有呢
I wish.
知道不
You know what?
现在的女孩子们注重男生的外貌
Girls like the cool guys now,
但是假以时日
but give it a few years.
她们就会移情睿智的男生
They start liking the smart guys.
届时会出现你的真命天女
You'll be all right.
能替我保密吗
Can you keep a secret?
当然  这是我的工作职责
I have to. It's my job.
我被诅咒了  真的
I'm cursed. I'm not kidding.
你知道孩子们玩的通灵游戏吗
This seance thing the kids did?
拼出了我的名字
It spelled out my name.
他们说我今年会死
Said I was gonna die.
拼出的是名还是姓
First name and last name?
楼上有个叫盖布的已年衰岁暮  病入膏肓
We've got a Gabe upstairs who's very old, very sick.
不是别人  就是我  一直倒霉的孩子
No. It's me. I have the worst luck.
有次我把镜子打碎了
One time I broke this mirror,
结果第二周我父母就分居了
the next week my parents got separated.
我的父母也分开了
My parents split up too.
孩子们都将其归咎于自己  其实不然
Every kid feels like it's his fault. It never is.
那你还遇见过什么倒霉事啊
So, what about the rest of the stuff?
有没有过背着父母在外面偷偷玩啊
Any playing outside your parents don't know about?
诸如此类的
Anything like that?
或者去了一些不该去的地方
Maybe you were somewhere you weren't supposed to be?
天哪
Oh, man.
盖布  这很重要
Gabe, it's important.
一个秘密基地
A secret club.
什么秘密  他们都是傻子吗
What's the secret they're all morons?
他在阁楼摔倒了  刮伤了手臂
He fell on something in the attic, scraped his arm,
结果第二天就出了皮疹
got the rash the next day.
他说那里霉味很重
Said it smelled really moldy up there.
未入洞穴  就得了真菌性肺炎
Fungal pneumonia without the cave.
-聪明  -我去取样
- Clever. - I'm gonna get a sample.
奇斯医生
Dr. Chase,
现在有空吗
you have a few moments?
抱歉  我得出去
Sorry, I've gotta go.
这些菜鸟医生  就不会以人为本
These young doctors. It's like they don't care about people.
-目无尊长  -或许是我的错
- No manners. - My fault, probably.
你的口音真有意思
That's an interesting accent you have there.
听来像是在澳洲生活30年的捷克人
I'd say Czech... with about 30 years of Aussie.
你还真是耳聪目明
You have quite an ear.
你是奇斯的父亲吧
You're Chase's dad.
他竟没有热烈拥抱你
Hard to miss, you know, the big hug
也未显示出兴奋之情
and how happy he was to see you.
-请求会诊  -会诊中
- Need a consult. - With a patient.
医生的紧急事件
Urgent doctor stuff.
26岁男性  突然失去言语功能
Twenty-six-year-old male, sudden loss of the ability to speak-
你是不用出门诊
Just because you got out of clinic duty
可我还得出门诊哎
doesn't mean everybody did.
是在他父亲面前
To his father.
-鉴别诊断  -是奇斯吗
- Differential diagnosis? - Chase?
老爸前脚进门  奇斯后脚就出门了
Dad swoops in, Chase swoops out.
他爸有没有说他此行的目的?
Dad say why he was here?
瞧  你都会关心一下
See? You asked.
老爸不远千里来此
Dad comes 5,000 miles,
你比他儿子还关心他此行的目的
you're more curious than junior is.
肯定不是来说离婚那事儿的
Can't just be about the divorce.
都离了15年  他母亲死了都有10年了
It's been 15 years, and mom's been dead for 10 of them.
难道是他爸杀了他妈
You think daddy murdered her?
如果想追根究底
You want to get to the bottom of this,
这倒是条正路
you're doing it exactly right
别和当事人谈
Don't talk to the people involved.
为了些无关的揣测将你的哥们儿从工作中拖出
Drag your buddy away from work for some pointless speculation.
要是你想知道两个化学物质之间会起何种反应
You want to know how two chemicals interact,
你会直接去问他们吗
do you ask them?
不会  因为他们会用化学小嘴撒谎
No. They're gonna lie through their lying little chemical teeth.
所以把他们扔进烧杯里  加热就行
Throw them in a beaker and apply heat.
真受不了你
Even I don't like you.
你说话真伤人
You know, words can hurt.
冷静  冷静  孩子们
Whoa, whoa, whoa, hold on, guys.
我不是来抓你们的
I don't care that you're up here.
你是警察吗
You a cop?
我是盖布·莱里克的医生
Doctor. I'm treating Gabe Reilich.
他说他在一些管道附近跌倒了
He said he fell over near some pipes?
是的  就在那
Yeah, over there.
-这里吗  -是的
- What, here? - Yeah.
最近你们有人生病吗
Any of you guys been feeling sick lately?
-类似皮疹  感冒之类的  -没有
- Rash, cold, anything? - No.
-糟了  他是条子  -靠
- Oh, crap. He is a cop! - Damn it!
他跌倒这种特殊的绝缘材料上
He fell on it, some weird kind of insulation.
这所房子建于60年代  有些陈旧
It's old. House was built in the '60s.
什么成分
What's it made of?
棉织物的纤维  还是毛毡
Felt, fibers of what, cotton?
抱歉  忘了你爸原来是那么幽默
Sorry. Forgotten how funny your dad was.
-远不及你  -过奖了
- Not as funny as you. - High praise.
我清楚孩子们对父母的防御心
I know how protective kids can be of their parents.
不是棉织物  是动物毛发
Not cotton. Animal hair.
把CT扫描拿给我
Get me the C.T. Scan.
首先  找出制造这种绝缘材料的公司
First, find the name of the company that made the insulation,
其次
And second,
眼前这一切让我想卖出他们的股票
tell me what I'm seeing that makes me want to short their stock.
淋巴结肿大
Uh, enlarged hilar lymph nodes.
-支气管增厚  -胸膜腔积液
- Peribronchial thickening. - Pleural effusions.
藏的越深越可怕
Less obvious, more scary.
纵隔膜看起来不对劲
Well, the mediastinum doesn't look right.
有点宽
Slightly widened.
天哪
Oh, god.
它可以通过动物皮毛传染
It can be transmitted through infected animal hair.
-但是革兰氏染色检测时应该会发现啊  -不
- But the gram's stain would have shown - No.
头孢呋辛会杀死部分病菌
The cefuroxime would have killed some of it,
导致结果产生偏差
clouded the result.
我们得对他用左氧沙星
We've gotta get this kid on levaquin.
他得的是什么病
What does he have?
炭疽  这屋子是老侯赛因的吗[暗示萨达姆]
Anthrax. This house belong to old man Hussein?
或许他确实被诅咒了
Maybe he is cursed.
炭疽  你是说那间阁楼曾住过恐怖分子吗
Anthrax. So, what-you think there were terrorists in that attic?
这是一种天然产生的细菌
It's a naturally occurring bacteria.
我们认为它存在于绝缘材料里
We believe it was in the insulation.
他的病情有多严重
How sick is he?
炭疽非常危险
Anthrax is very dangerous,
不过我们及时发现
but we've caught it early.
我们对他用了左氧沙星
He's on levaquin.
这是医院里最好的抗生素
It's the best antibiotic we have.
丽莎  你相信吗
Lisa, you buy this?
杰弗  你对我们医院做出了巨大的贡献
Jeff, you've helped our hospital a lot.
如果对豪斯医生没有信心的话
I wouldn't have assigned Dr.House to your case
我是不会让他治疗令郎的
if I didn't have every confidence in him.
-那他是谁  -杰弗里
- Then who's this guy? - Jeffrey!
很多怪病都可能会引发皮疹
There's all these weird diseases that can cause a rash.
你们考虑过利什曼病和丝虫病吗
What about leishmaniasis or filariasis?
-你从哪里听来的  -网上  我做了些调查
- Where'd you hear about those? - Internet. I did some research.
那些病极其罕见
Well, those are very rare conditions.
难道炭疽病四处蔓延吗
Oh, and anthrax grows along the interstate?
利什曼病不会引发肺炎  而丝虫病...
Leishmaniasis doesn't cause pneumonia, and filariasis-
希望你们能面面俱到  这可是我儿子
Just look into everything. This is my son, all right?
我儿子不好
And I'm gonna stay on top of you
你们一个都跑不了
until I know he's safe.
我也希望他能康复
I wouldn't expect anything else.
医生满地爬啊
Everyone's a doctor.
呼吸  宝贝  没事的  呼吸
Breathe, baby. It's okay. Breathe. I need you to breathe.
-他喘不动气  -吸气困难
-His breathing - It's on the inhale.
-什么意思  -他的呼吸道痉挛
- What does that mean? - It means his airway's closing up.
是炭疽病导致的吗
Is the anthrax doin' it?
别动  盖布
All right. Hold still, Gabe.
可能会有些不舒服
This is gonna be a little uncomfortable.
我们会治好你的  别担心
We've got you. It's okay.
-喉咙里有结节  -气道堵塞吗
- Nodules in his throat. - Airway's occluded?
-需要插管  注射氯羟安定  -注射3毫升
- We've got to intubate. Ativan! - Pushing 3 C.C.'s.
气道痉挛
Airway's too tight.
怎么回事  怎么回事
What's wrong? What's wrong?
住手  你们这群凶手
No, you're killing him!
-杰弗里  别插手  -气道痉挛
- Jeffrey! Let them do their job. - Airway's too tight.
小号的气管插管
Get me a smaller tube.
-气管切开吧  -拿根小号的
- We're traching. - Smaller tube.
-他的嘴唇发紫  -他呼吸停止了
- His lips are cyanotic. - He's not breathing.
福曼  气管切开吧
Foreman, we're traching.
不  我能行  我能插进去
No. I can do it. I'll get it.
-福曼  你插不进去的  -他已经缺氧了
- Foreman, you're not getting through. - He's not getting air.
现在就得气管切开
We have to trach him right now.
不  我能插进去
No, I can do it.
碘酒
Betadine.
我要切了
I'm doing this.
好了
Got it.
他没事了
He's okay.
对抗生素过敏吗
Allergic reaction to the antibiotics?
我觉得不是
I don't think so.
我们给他换成利福平了
We switched him to rifampin,
肿胀也没有消失
and there was no change in the swelling.
我们应该试试其他的抗生素
We should try another antibiotic.
真的会同时对两种抗生素过敏吗
You really think he's allergic to two antibiotics?
我想听听奇斯医生的想法
I wanna know what Dr. Chase thinks.
他对两种抗生素过敏是...
It's possible he's allergic
抱歉  没说你
Oh! I'm sorry. Not you.
不怪你  不过我说的是另一位奇斯医生
Understandable mistake. The other Dr. Chase.
一名男童得了炭疽并同时对两种抗生素过敏
Boy gets anthrax and happens to be allergic to two antibiotics.
无意冒犯任何人
Hate to step on anybody's toes,
不过会不会是你们之前的诊断有误呢
but is it possible your guys got this one wrong?
皮疹是炭疽病的一个主要症状
The rash is classic anthrax.
你忘记考虑颜色了
Except the color.
皮疹还没变黑  没有坏死就不是炭疽
The rash hasn't turned black yet. No necrosis, no anthrax.
理论上来说  坏死要两周
Necrosis can theoretically take as long as two weeks.
伙计们  诊断第一  比赛第二
Guys, it's not a competition. It's a diagnosis.
谁赞同小奇斯
Okay. Who thinks junior wins?
4比1  不是炭疽
Four to one. It's not anthrax.
重来  什么变了  结节说明了什么
So we start over. What's changed? What do the nodules tell us?
-肉状瘤病  -很好  给你打个A
- Sarcoidosis. - Excellent. Send an ace level.
如果检查结果呈阳性  给他用甲氨蝶呤
If it comes back positive, put him on methotrexate.
一些检验结果表明是肉状瘤病
We ran some tests and the results point toward sarcoidosis.
从而导致一些身体组织肿胀
It makes the body's tissues swell up.
看来蔓延到了盖布的皮肤和肺部
It seems to have gone after Gabriel's skin and lungs
进而导致他发烧
and given him this fever.
医生
Doctor.
目前我们还不知道病因
We don't know what causes it.
不过你确定他得的是这个病吗
But you're sure he has this one?
我们这里有一名世界级的名医做顾问
We have a world-renowned doctor consulting.
-他坚信这是肉状瘤病  -那这病有治吗
- He's convinced this is sarcoidosis. - Is it treatable?
很简单  这是静脉注射甲氨蝶呤
Very, actually. See, this is I.V.Methotrexate.
这是一种消炎药
It's an anti-inflammatory.
它可以消肿
It should make all the swelling go down and,
治好你的病
uh, get you all better.
等等
Stop.
天哪  变黑了
My god, it's black.
坏死
Necrosis.
表面症状肯定是炭疽
It's definitely anthrax,
综合起来也肯定不是炭疽
and it definitely can't be anthrax.
炭疽不会导致喉咙结节
It doesn't cause throat nodules.
唯一合理的解释
Only explanation is,
这个孩子同时得了炭疽病和肉瘤
this kid's got anthrax and sarcoidosis.
是啊  两种罕见疾病
Right, two incredibly rare diseases...
同时发在一个人身上
just happening to strike at once.
你还有其他高见吗
Unless you've got a better theory.
炭疽并发过敏反应
Anthrax plus an allergic reaction.
打电话给《柳叶刀》  这里有一项罕见病症
Call The Lancet, because that's one bizarre allergic reaction.
别这样  你俩总得有一个是对的吧
Come on. There's no reason you both can't be wrong.
不是过敏也不是巧合
It's not allergy, but it's not coincidence either.
疾病一引发了疾病二
Disease number one set off disease number two.
炭疽破坏了他的免疫系统
Anthrax weakened his immune system.
同时引发了潜在肉状瘤
And triggered a dormant sarcoidosis.
继续使用抗生素对付炭疽
Keep him on antibiotics for the anthrax,
再加上治疗肉瘤的甲氨蝶呤
and start the methotrexate for the sarcoidosis.
看看结果如何
See what happens.
好吧
Fine.
最好跟着他
Better go with him.
以防他草率行事  伤及无辜
Make sure he doesn't snap and hurt somebody.
你们同时治疗两种病
Yeah, but y-you're treating him for both diseases.
我们得面面俱到
We're covering all the bases.
把东西都砸向墙上  看哪个能粘上去吗
What? Throw everything against the wall and see what sticks?
意大利面能粘上去
Works for spaghetti.
你在开玩笑吗
A-are you being funny?
显然不是
Apparently not.
知道我为什么给这家医院捐款吗
You know why I give money to this hospital?
唯有此才能引人重视  瞧这儿
It's the only way to get attention. See this?
你这是在变魔术吗
Is this a magic trick?
我可是大卫·科波菲尔的忠实粉丝
'cause I am a total David Copperfield fan.
不过我觉得《火旋风》那个魔术
Although I thought that
做的有点假
tornado of fire- that seemed a little fake.
我的手腕疼痛了几个月
Pain in the wrist. It won't go away for months.
6名医生的高见是没毛病
Six doctors' brilliant conclusion is to take it easy.
我捐款后  立刻榜上有名
I write a check, name goes on a plaque,
48小时后
And 48 hours later
我做了两次核磁共振  一次骨扫描
I've got two M.R.I.'s, a bone scan
被确诊为腕管综合征
and a diagnosis: carpal tunnel.
当天下午我就进了手术室
I'm in surgery that afternoon.
真是曲折离奇啊
Fascinating story.
有没有想过改编成舞台剧啊
Have you thought of adapting it for the stage?
我爱我...  听我说  我爱我的儿子
I love my look at me. I love my son.
我对他的爱无可取代
I love him more than anything else in the world.
你必须重视这个病例
And you are gonna start paying attention to this case,
否则我会让你痛不欲生
or I'm gonna make things miserable
-回你儿子的病房  -在引起你重视前
-Go back to your son's room. -I'm not leaving here
-我是不会...  -有情况了
- until you get your ass - There's a problem.
怎么回事
What is it?
不知道
I don't know.
皮肤损害蔓延至全身
Skin lesions are spreading all over his body.
损伤破裂  脂肪组织液化
They're opening up, and the fatty tissues are oozing out.
不假时日  他会皮肤溃烂
He'll be septic in a matter of days.
死于皮炎
Death by dermatitis.
-罗伯特去哪了  -他今早要去门诊
- Where's Robert? - Uh, he has clinic duty this morning.
不用了
No, he doesn't.
我重新安排了你们的日程  你们没事了
I rescheduled you guys so you'd be free.
不过  他又重新安排了自己的日程
Yeah, but he re-rescheduled himself.
-现在还不疼  -继续
-It doesn't hurt yet. - Keep going.
你呼我了吗
You page me?
-没啊  这里不需要你  -别这样
- No, I don't need you. - Come on.
独木难支  孤掌难鸣啊
We all need help now and again.
我们要对你进行会诊
You're getting a consult.
病人新发皮肤病变
Okay. We've got new skin lesions,
范围扩散  情况也更严重
bigger and uglier.
-病因是什么  -我的手疼
- What would cause that? - My hand hurts.
如果他的身体努力去抵御炭疽病毒
What if his body worked so hard attacking
而产生的抗体又攻击他的身体
the anthrax that it started attacking itself?
-自身免疫  -不会如此严重
- Autoimmune. - Wouldn't present this aggressively.
看上去是不像  但是有这个可能
It's not likely, but it is possible.
是吗  一个12岁的男孩会得这种病
What, in a twelve-year-old male?
你们说的不是我吧
This isn't about me, is it?
盖布的爸爸昨天在网上搜到利什曼病和丝虫病
Gabe's dad found  leishmaniasis and filariasis on the internet yesterday.
那时的症状不符  不过现在症状与之相符
They didn't fit then, but now they kind of do.
是啊  除了结节
Sure, except for the nodules,
我们又不是在加尔各答工作
and we're not working out of Calcutta General.
多发性神经纤维瘤病
Multiple neurofibromatosis.
你认为他的病因是神经性的吗
You think this is neurological?
你认为是免疫系统的问题
The only reason you're thinking
仅仅是因为你是风湿病学家
autoimmune is because you're a rheumatologist.
如果是直肠病学家  你会诊断为直肠癌
If you were a proctologist, you'd think rectal cancer.
得听老奇斯的
Gotta go with senior.
他曾为此写了本书
He literally wrote the book on this one.
免疫系统纷繁复杂
Autoimmune is a big universe.
从硬皮病到变应性肉芽肿  均有可能
It could be anything from scleroderma to churg-strauss.
无论病因是什么
Whatever it is,
我们应该给他用类固醇消肿
we should start him on steroids, keep the swelling down.
100毫克的环磷酰胺能极大的修复免疫系统
A hundred milligrams of cytoxan it treats most autoimmunes.
好  赶在脂肪从他的眼中溢出前给他用药吧
Well, give it to him now before the fat starts dripping out his eyeballs.
我的手指麻木了
Hey, my fingers are numb.
表戴得太紧了
Your watch is on too tight.
你让我很混乱
You're messing with my head.
你和你爸的关系
Your relationship with your dad is
使你的工作大受干扰
messing with your ability to do your job.
那是你让我爸参与我的工作中
Only because you made my dad part of my job.
说的好  你们多年未见
Good point. You haven't seen him in years,
他为看你不远万里  横跨大西洋
he flies across the Atlantic to see you
是太平洋
Pacific.
可你对他避之不及
You breeze by him like he's a Hare Krishna at the airport,
该会徒经常在机场和公共场所乞求施舍或者卖花
卖他们的印刷刊物
你甚至都没问他此行的目的
You don't even ask why he's in town.
可能是来参会议吧
It's probably a conference.
可能
Probably.
本来我想一手包办
I was hoping to do this through sheer manipulation,
可如果你坚持对话  好吧  说吧
but if you insist on talking, fine. Talk.
他曾经对你做过什么
What did he do to you?
如果我干涉你的私生活  你做何感想
How would you feel if I interfered in your personal life?
我非常痛恨  所以我没私生活
I'd hate it- that's why I cleverly have no personal life.
我要替他的皮肤病灶做活检
I'm gonna biopsy his skin lesions.
有想法  想办法证明你爸错了
Good thinking. Prove your dad wrong.
那就解决所有事了
That'll solve everything.
-谁替他拔了管  -我拔的
- Who extubated him? - I did.
体温下降了两度
Temperature's down two degrees,
皮肤肿胀也几乎消失了
and the swelling's almost gone.
他的皮肤看上去也好多了
And his skin looks better too.
环磷酰胺起作用了
Cytoxan is working.
-感觉好多了吗  盖布  -好多了
- Feeling better, Gabe? - Yep, a lot.
奇斯医生  借一步说话
Dr. Chase, can you and I have a word?
你的诊断错误  不是自身免疫性疾病
Your diagnosis is wrong. No autoimmune disease.
肿胀消失
The swelling's probably just down
可能是因为类固醇起作用了
because we've got him on steroids.
掩盖了真正的病因
It's masking whatever's really wrong.
A.N.A.结果可能有误
A.N.A.'s are unreliable.
抗心磷脂抗体检测结果是阴性
Phospholipid antibodies are negative,
不是狼疮  也不会是变应性肉芽肿血管炎
so no lupus. Same for churg-strauss.
你在和一名风湿病学家辩论
You're arguing with a rheumatologist.
大概有20种独特的自身免疫性疾病
There's about 20 distinct autoimmune diseases-
你为什么来这里
Why are you here?
来参加红斑狼疮学术会议
S.L.E. Conference.
去年你去纽约参加硬皮病研究会议
You were in New York last year for the scleroderma conference.
那时你可没来探望我啊
I didn't hear anything from you.
这次只是过来跟你打声招呼
Just wanted to say hi this time.
说完了  怎么还不走
You said it. You're still here.
我想你
I miss you.
你离家那年我才15岁
I was 15 years old when you walked out.
现在你又想回来吗
Now you're walking back in?
我离开了你母亲  可我没有离开你
I left your mother. I didn't leave you.
你走后妈妈每天喝的酩酊烂醉
Mum was living on gin and tonics.
那时我根本无力照顾她
How was I supposed to take care of her?
这不是你的责任
She wasn't your responsibility.
是的  照顾她是你的责任
I know! She was yours.
对于她的去世我很抱歉
I'm sorry she died.
我很抱歉让你独自面对这一切
I'm sorry you had to deal with that.
但是很久之前  她就精神失常了
But she was falling apart long before-
我得去和豪斯讨论治疗方案
I've got to talk to House about this treatment.
但是病人逐渐好转
But the patient's getting better.
尽管用的是环磷酰胺
In spite of the cytoxan.
另一方面  他已有所好转
On the other hand getting better.
环磷酰胺导致他更易被感染
Cytoxan makes him more susceptible to infection.
炭疽可能会故态复萌  变本加厉
The anthrax could relapse and be more resistant.
好转了啊
Better!
你希望所有与自身免疫性疾病相关的
You want a negative test
化验结果都为阴性吗
for every autoimmune disease known to man?
好  我会让你称心的
Fine. I'll get 'em.
午夜前不回家  这周末就不给你车
Be home by midnight or you can't have the car this weekend.
父子俩叙旧没
You guys talk?
他有没有告诉你他此行的目的
Did he tell you why he's here?
他来参加红斑狼疮研讨会
The S.L.E. Conference.
回去参加会议去吗
Going back to the conference?
是下午的会议  但愿别睡着
Afternoon panel. I hope I can stay awake.
但愿你能进场
I hope you can get in.
参会人员上没有你的名字
You're not registered.
我懂的  你得编造一个谎言
I get it. You had to make up a lie.
因为你不能告诉奇斯你是来看他的
Can't just tell your kid you're here to see him.
哪个当爹的会这么做啊
I mean, what father does that?
你领子下面的那个小蓝点
That little blue dot under your collar-
说明你在做放疗
It's a tattoo for guiding radiation treatment.
看你早上吃糙米和蔬菜后
I was looking for it after I saw what
我就在找寻它
you had for breakfast: brown rice, vegetables.
这种延寿饮食的簇拥者
It's a macrobiotic diet
主要遍布于好莱坞明星以及...
popular with Hollywood starlets and...
癌症患者
Cancer patients.
晚期肺癌
Lungs. Stage iv.
-你看上去挺不错  -其实不好
- You look good. - I'm not.
我来美国是为了去斯隆－凯特琳癌症中心
Came to the States to go to Sloan-Kettering
以及拜访威尔森医生
and see Dr. Wilson.
-他怎么说  -我还有三个月
- What'd he say? - Three months.
可你对罗伯特却只字未提
But you haven't told Robert.
你不想给他平添负担
You don't want to burden him,
因为你是个不称职的父亲
because you were such a lousy dad.
请别告诉他
I'd prefer you not tell him.
是啊  这样好点
Yeah. That's better.
想象的出当他得知他父亲死讯时的心情
I'll get to see his face when he reads his dad's obituary.
这与你无关
It's not your business.
是与我无关
I suppose it isn't.
你肯定做过不少化验吧
You sure do a lot of tests.
如能查明你的病因
If we figure out exactly which autoimmune condition it is,
你就能尽早恢复了
we can get you better quicker.
-之前那个人是你爸吗  -是的
- Was that your dad before? - Yeah.
太酷了  你们经常一起工作吗
That's so cool. Do you guys work together a lot?
不是
Not really.
我什么时候才能回家呀
When can I go home?
看情况吧
We'll see.
看来你的胃口恢复了  这是个好现象
Looks like you got your appetite back. That's a good sign.
-喝水吗 -恩
- Want some water? - Yes.
拿着
Here you go.
啊哦  没关系  水不值钱
Whoops. That's all right. Water's cheap.
-天哪  -怎么了
- Oh, god. - What?
手不能动了
I can't- I can't move my hand.
能抓住我的手指吗  盖布
Can you squeeze my fingers for me, Gabe?
他的病情恶化了
He's getting worse.
他的右手和前臂都已失去知觉
Now his entire right hand and forearm are paralyzed.
他又发烧了  体温高达华氏105度
And his fever's back. It's up over 105.
如果我们不能尽快阻止神经退化
If we don't stop the nerve deterioration quickly,
他将会终身残废
he'll be paralyzed for life.
幸运的是
Well, luckily,
以此恶化速度  他活不过一周
at this rate that should only last about a week.
那么...
Okay. So
我说过我们应该放弃使用环磷酰胺
I told you we should get him off the cytoxan.
这是神经中毒
This is toxic neuropathy.
我们随意给他用药
We've been shoving drugs into his system
去治疗莫须有的病
for a disease he doesn't have.
但它可能是神经性的
Well, it could be neurological.
哪种脑部疾病会导致手部麻痹
What kind of brain process would cause a paralyzed hand,
皮肤病变以及喉咙肿结节
skin lesions and swollen throat nodules?
罗伯特先前说的对
Robert was right.
是多发性神经纤维瘤病
You said multiple neurofibromatosis.
这么说是为了家庭的和谐美满
Are you saying that for the chance at a beautiful family moment,
还是理性的医疗建议
or is there some medicine involved?
-症状更加符合啊  -真遗憾
- Fits better. - Too bad.
我还以为你是为了家庭美满呢
I was hoping for the other reason.
我正要去拿摄像机拍下这激动人心的一刻
I was gonna go get my camera.
这次去做脑扫描
Get a C.T. Scan- his brain this time.
你觉得三份就够了  是吗
You'd think three copies would be enough, right?
一份我都觉得绰绰有余
One's always been more than enough for me.
你为什么没有告诉我罗文·奇斯是来找你的
Why didn't you tell me that Rowan Chase was in to see you?
失陪
Excuse me.
职业道德  病人保密条约
Ethics, confidentiality-
这些都能成为理由吧
does any of this ring a bell?
你本可以叫我来会诊以掩护你自己
You could have covered yourself, called me in for a consult.
这又不是什么热门八卦
It is a juicy piece of gossip.
知道吗
You know what happened?
我全神贯注检查他的癌症没想那么多
I got all focused on his cancer and lost perspective.
你不能告诉奇斯  但我可以
You can't tell Chase, but I can.
我该怎么做呢
What should I do?
貌似是到我得给你建议
This is where I give you advice and
并假装你会听这一环节了
pretend you're gonna listen to it.
我喜欢这一环节
I like this part.
罗文让你别说了吗
Did Rowan ask you not to tell?
我答应替他保守秘密
I promised I wouldn't.
我是答应他了  不过我现在我又反悔了
My fingers were crossed, though, so I'm wide open.
我错了  原来这是自娱自乐环节
I was wrong. This is the musing-out-loud part.
-貌似我的存在都是多余的  -告诉他
- Do I actually need to be here? - Telling him.
这就相当的具有娱乐性了
Now, that's got real entertainment value.
是啊  他可能会声泪俱下
He might even cry.
有种东西叫做  己所不欲  勿施于人
On the other hand, there is the do-unto-others thingy.
那我更应该告诉他  因为我就很想知道
Well, then I should definitely tell him. I'd wanna know.
你什么都想知道
You wanna know everything.
还有一种东西就是做人要守信用
There's also the keeping-your-promises thingy.
您身边可是金发东西团团转啊
You never run out of thingies like that blonde thingy you were chatting up.
是医院的会计师
She's the hospital accountant.
我们在讨论账单的问题
We were going over billing procedures.
泡妞专用的复式记账法吗
Double-entry bookkeeping?
你打算怎么做
What are you gonna do?
账单的问题  真复杂  对吧
Billing procedures. They're so complicated, aren't they?
父母通常没有孩子们想的那么坏
You know, parents are never as bad as kids think they are.
那么喜欢我爸  约他出去好了
If you like my dad so much, ask him out.
我肯定会是个好后妈
I'd make an excellent stepmom.
我宽宏大度
I'm very lenient.
他是你爸
He's your father.
你不曾有机会了解他  可他现在就这里
You never see him, and he's here.
若非他曾做过一些不堪入目的事
Unless he's done some unspeakable thing,
你应该释怀
you should lighten up.
很好  多谢提醒
Great. Thanks for the tip.
好吧
Okay.
他对你妈施暴  对你施暴
He beat your mom. He beat you.
-他到底做了什么  -说真的  别逼我
- What did he do? - Really, don't push it.
由怨生恨  终噬己身
All this hate. It's toxic.
那离我远点
Then stay away.
没有发现
There's nothing there.
没有包块  没有纤维缠结  什么都没有
No masses, no fibrous tangles, nothing.
不是神经纤维瘤
It's not neurofibromatosis.
奇斯医生们屡战屡败
Drs. Chase are 0 for 3.
即便他们达成一致了  他们也错
Even when they agree, they're wrong.
那么什么病会导致神经损伤和结节一样
So, next, what else could cause neural damage as well as all the nodules?
伯格氏病
Berger's disease.
他不曾出国
He's never been out of the country.
父母呢
Have his parents?
他们可能是传染源
They could have brought it back.
-我可不这么认为  -没关系
- I don't think so. - It doesn't matter.
他的脓包不该出现在那里
His lesions are in the wrong place.
他的双脚却没有病变
His feet are the one clear spot.
孩子他爸曾提及利什曼病
Kid's dad mentioned leishmaniasis.
还提了丝虫病
Yeah, and filariasis.
可喉部的结节与病症不符啊
But the throat nodules still don't fit with that.
这两种病几乎仅现于东南亚
That's two diseases pretty much exclusive to Southeast Asia.
如果第二种疾病不是由炭疽引发的呢
What if the anthrax didn't set off the second disease?
-又回到巧合上面来了吗  -不是
- We're back at coincidence again? - No.
如果导火索是其他病呢
What if something else was the trigger?
-没有其他症状  -我们做过些治疗
- Nothing else happened. - We happened.
-抗生素吗  -我们已经讨论过了
- Antibiotics? - We've been through this.
这不是过敏
It's not an allergy.
我要去撒尿
I gotta pee.
-你们从CT扫描中得知什么  -一无所获
- What did the C.T. Scan tell you? - Nothing.
十分制  你的疼痛程度有几分
Ow! Scale from one to 10- how painful?
肯定没有打你一拳的一半疼
Not half as painful as when I punch you in the face.
别这样  你也会疼的
Don't do that. It'll hurt you.
腕管综合症手术显然没有奏效
Carpal tunnel surgery obviously didn't work.
你是谁
Who are you?
小孩子们都叫我格雷戈叔叔
The little ones call me uncle Greg.
你爸从未得过腕管综合症
Your dad never had carpal tunnel.
你之前向奇斯医生提过两种怪病
You mentioned two obscure diseases to Dr. Chase.
你从何得知
How did you know about them?
在网上看到的
I read about them on the internet.
那你的搜索关键词是?
What did you search for-
"不符我儿子病症的亚洲疾病"吗
" Diseases from Asia that don't match my son's symptoms"?
你曾在亚洲耳闻这些疾病
You heard about them in Asia.
我从未去过那里
I've never been there.
估计你忘了  提醒你一下吧
Well, you probably just forgot. Let me refresh your memory:
偏远肮脏的村庄  狭窄的住所
Some remote, dusty village, close quarters,
我猜待了至少有一年吧
at least a year?
-想起来没  -我要去叫卡迪医生
- Starting to come back? - I'm calling Dr. Cuddy.
请问这和我儿子的病情有关吗
Excuse me, what does this have to do with our son?
你爸毛了  不过他理应如此
Your dad's pissed off. He should be.
他希望我们尽十一分力替你治病
Comes here expecting us to do an extra-good job
就因为他捐赠巨款给医院
Because he gives a whole lot of money to this hospital.
别那么对我儿子说
Don't talk to my son like that!
我只是向他阐述我的工作职责
Just telling him my job and my obligation-
住嘴  怎么回事
Stop! What's going on?
你们别无选择
There's only one thing you guys have gotta do.
唯有说实话  否则你儿子就没命了
Tell the truth, or your son will die.
你在亚洲待了多久
How long were you in Asia?
杰弗  这问题不难啊
Jeff, it's a simple question.
在印度待了两年
Two years, in India.
你为何向我们隐瞒
Why would you lie about something like that?
那是87年和88年
It was '87 and '88.
我本以为
This, uh, this Guru-
古鲁能给予我启示
I-I thought he had some answers.
我曾拜访他的静修处[印度教]
I went to his ashram...
结果我赔了夫人又折兵
And, um, ended up with no money and no answers.
我无地自容  不想让别人知道
I was embarrassed. I didn't want anyone to know.
不会的
No.
不会的  你是一名空军试飞员
No. You were a test pilot.
很抱歉  盖布
I'm so sorry, Gabe.
这和我儿子的病情有何关联
What does this have to do with my son?
提示一  如果我是耶稣
Clue number one If I were Jesus,
治好这个孩子如将水变酒那般容易
curing this kid would be as easy as turning water into wine.
他是被鬼附体吗
Demonic possession?
接近答案  不过没有圣饼
Close, but no wafer.
提示二  风湿病学家罗文的观点基本正确
Clue number two Rheumatology Rowan was almost right.
这引发了自身免疫性疾病症状
It causes autoimmune symptoms.
麻风吗
Leprosy?
是啊  这在新泽西州郊区还真是多见啊
Yeah, that's real big in the Jersey suburbs.
的确是麻风  做个Fite染色
It's leprosy. Run a Fite stain.
结果肯定是阳性
It'll be positive.
老爸曾长期泡在不正规的印度静修处
Daddy hung out on the wrong kind of Indian ashram.
但显然是潜伏在父亲体内
But it's obviously dormant in the dad.
孩子怎么会染上
How could the kid catch it?
不是潜伏在父亲体内  只是缓慢发作而已
It's not dormant in the dad. It's just slow.
他的尺骨神经因此受损
Damaged his ulnar nerves.
可被误诊为腕管综合症
Was misdiagnosed as carpal tunnel.
永远别信医生  做个Fite染色
Never trust doctors. Run a Fite stain.
他会得炭疽也是顺理成章
No wonder he got anthrax.
麻风破坏了他的免疫系统
The leprosy weakened his immune system.
恶性循环  麻风增加了他感染炭疽的风险
Vicious circle: The leprosy made him vulnerable to the anthrax,
而治疗炭疽又加重麻风
and the anthrax treatment put the leprosy in overdrive.
-但是给他施用的抗生素会治好麻风  -是啊
- But the antibiotics we gave him they cure leprosy. - Yeah.
那就是麻烦的起因
That's where the trouble starts.
抗生素损伤了神经纤维
The antibiotics hit the nerve strands.
杀灭麻风病菌
They kill the leprosy bacteria,
而病菌残余进入体内循环系统
and the corpses get tossed into the system.
我们的身体构造惊奇神秘  但他们其实很蠢
And as fascinating as our bodies are, they're also stupid.
他们会产生抗体对抗已死的病菌
They produce antibodies to beat dead bacteria.
然而这些抗体绝非善类
And these aren't the polite antibodies.
他们不安分守己  当身体稍有懈怠便发动攻击
They're the ones that won't sit still, kick during nap time.
攻击他的神经和脂肪细胞
They attack his neural and fat cells,
从而引发炎症以及其他一些症状
Causing inflammation and all the rest of his symptoms.
也就是说我们的治疗反而伤害了他
So the cure's killing him.
给美国本土48州里最后一个麻风隔离所打电话
I want you to call down to Carville, Louisiana,
它位于路易斯安那的卡维尔
home of the last leper colony in the lower 48.
让他们送些反应停过来
Get 'em to send up some thalidomide.
-反应停  -他是12岁的处男吧
- Thalidomide? - Twelve-year-olds don't have sex, right?
原用作妊娠妇女的镇静药
但后来发现会引起胎儿四肢畸形而被禁用
所以不可能会怀孕嘛
So he can't be pregnant.
打电话去
Make the call.
我要和你儿子单独谈谈
I need to speak to your boy.
为什么人人都要管我的闲事
Why does everybody need to know my business?
人都爱嚼舌根
People like talking about people.
觉得自己高人一等  一切尽在掌握之中
Makes us feel superior, makes us feel in control,
有些时候  对于有些人
And sometimes, for some people,
了解情况可以引起他们的关心
knowing some things makes them care.
告诉你我爸弃我们而去  我妈酗酒致死
I tell you my dad left, my mum drank herself to death,
你就会加倍关心我了吗
You gonna care about me more?
卡梅隆会更加关心你
Cameron would.
而我就是好奇心强而已
Me, I just like knowing stuff.
我知道你恨你爸
I know you hate your dad.
-我得跟你说说  -我不恨他
- Now, I'm gonna tell you something- - I don't hate him.
当我发现不在意他反而不容易受伤后
I loved him until I figured out
我就不爱他了
that it hurts a lot less to just not care.
不期望他会在你的足球赛上出现
You don't expect him to turn up to your football match,
不会感到失望
no disappointments.
不期望在生日时接到他的电话
You don't expect a call on your birthday,
不期望见到他  没有失望
Don't expect to see him for months, no disappointments.
你希望我们重归于好
You want us to go make up-
杯酒言欢  嘘寒问暖吗
sink a few beers together, nice family hug?
我对他抱有过多的希望
I've given him enough hugs.
可他给了我太多的失望
He's given me enough disappointments.
好吧
Okay.
-说完了吗  -说完了
- That's it? - That's it.
深呼吸
Breathe.
Breathe again.
深呼吸
你会告诉我的朋友们我得了麻风吗
Are you gonna have to tell my friends I'm a leper?
已经对你施用了抗生素
You had the antibiotics.
不会传染给别人的
You're not contagious anymore.
如果他们已经得了呢
Well, what if they already caught it?
麻风极其罕见  即便你妈都没得过
Leprosy is incredibly hard to catch. Even your mum didn't get it.
好了  握拳试试
Right. I want you to make a fist.
还是有点僵硬
It's still kinda stiff.
一两个月后就能恢复正常了
It'll get back to normal in a month or two.
你的皮肤两三周就能好
Your skin, two or three weeks.
你一直没询问你父亲的情况
You haven't asked about your dad.
他满嘴谎言
He lied about everything.
他欺骗了我妈  欺骗了他的上司
He lied to my mom. He lied to his boss.
他是个彻头彻尾的骗子
He's just a liar.
他爱你
He loves you.
我不爱他
I don't love him.
你爱他
Yeah, you do.
这是既定的事实  他是你爸
Nothing you can do about it. He's your dad.
无论他做了什么  你都爱他
It doesn't matter what he does. You're gonna love him.
就到这里  谢谢
Here. Thanks.
几点的飞机  有时间喝一杯吗
When's your flight? You got time for a drink?
没时间
Wish I did.
奇斯医生
Dr. Chase?
我帮你拿
I got it.
什么时候回澳洲
You're gonna be gettin' down to Oz anytime soon?
很快  但愿明年秋天能去
Not too long. Next autumn, I hope.
到时给你打电话
I'll call ya.
好了  一切就绪
Well, you're all set.
到时见
I'll see ya.
I'll see you.